Guide to the Robert Grenier Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series VI. RG Critical Writings 1960 - 1998, Being notes, papers, essays, reviews, verse commentaries, speculative jottings, etc., dated/ chronologized and counted (by pages of text) in folders. 1 box.
  - C. RG Critical Writings, 1970 - 1998
    - 77. RG 4-color holograph Drawing note on xerox technology & RG r h y m m s project, 1994 July 6, w/ black & white xerox image of same (2 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 015)
    - 78. RG notes toward talk given at SUNY/Buffalo, 1994 Oct 6 "LARRY EIGNER AND THE TASK OF AMERICAN LETTERS", (3 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 015)
      - RG holograph notes marked "5-6 AM OCT 6/94 & OCT 9 adds", (xerox) w/ RG holograph addition
      - Two xeroxes of RG final holograph version
    - 79. RG 'review' of Don Byrd's The Poetics Of The Common Knowledge (SUNY/Albany Press, 1993) dated 1994 Oct 31Pub. in Witz, Vol. 3. No. 2 (Spring 1995), (6 pp. total) (Box 015)
      - RG holograph first Draft
      - RG ts. final Draft (w/ xerox of same)
    - 80. RG Afterword to Larry Eigner's readiness / enough / depends / on (Sun & Moon Press, 1999), ed. RG, (14 pp. total) (Box 015)
      - RG color holograph first Draft
      - RG ts./color holograph final Draft, dated 1996 Feb 9, (w/ black & white xerox version of same, as pub. in book)
      - RG related color holograph notation, "HALCYON DAYS FEB 11-13/96" from week following Larry Eigner's death
        (unpublished)
    - 81. RG ts. "BRIEF ACCOUNT OF GRENIER/EIGNER MATERIALS", dated 1996 Oct 6, written for Stanford Library at time of deposit there by RG of Larry Eigner Archive materials, (4 pp. total) (unpublished xerox) (Box 015)
    - 82. Two RG letters to Kenneth Irby re 'Romanticism' etca. from 1997 July, (14 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 015)
      - RG holograph letter to KI, 1997 July 10, (xerox)
      - RG holograph letter to KI, 1997 July 12, (xerox)
    - 83. RG color holograph description of RG's OWL / ON / BOU / GH (Post-Apollo Press, 1997), (1st Draft) (1 p. total) (Box 015)
      Written for Small Press Distribution catalogue.
    - 84. RG note "ON THE EMPTY / SUBLIME", dated 1997 Nov 18, (11 pp. total) (Box 015)
      Pub. in Laura Moriarty's online zine non 2
      - RG color holograph first Draft
      - RG print-out second Draft, w/ RG holograph addition
      - RG print-out third Draft, w/ RG holograph revision
      - Print-out of version of note in non 2 1998 Apr 4
    - 85. RG color holograph note, "POSTSCRIPT TO 'SUBLIME'", dated 1998 Jan 1, (6 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 015)
    - 86. RG introduction to David Bromige's As in T as in Tethered (Chax Press, 2002), 1988 Nov 11 - 1998 Nov 12, (12 pp. total) (Box 015)
      - RG color holograph first Draft
      - RG ts. second Draft, w/ RG holograph revisions
      - RG ts. third Draft, w/ RG holograph revision, (w/ xerox of same)
- Series VII. Miscellaneous RG Poetry Manuscripts 1966 - 1998, Various holograph and typescript material, collected and uncollected, dated/chronologized and identified by reference to period of RG's writing, and counted (by pages of text) in folders. 1 box.
  - A. RG holograph & ts. poetic material from France, England & Iowa 1966 Fall - 1967 Fall, (mostly written while on Amy Lowell Travelling Scholarship (unpublished & annotated by RG "diffuse/verbose dreck")) (107 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - B. RG holograph poem "Warm", written ca. May 1967 (in Southwold, Suffolk, Emily pregnant w/ Amy), pub. in Poetry (Chicago), Vol. 112, No. 2 (May 1968) & collected in RG's Series (This Press, 1978), (1 p. total) (see also chapbook in XII.A. below) (Box 016)
  - C. RG broadside poem beginning "worldly goods..." from [ca. 1969], (collected in unpublished book ms. Water Farmer, in section VIII. below) (1 p. total) (Box 016)
  - D. Three RG selections/organizations exploring spatial arrangements of poetic material from [ca. 1971], (21 pp. total) (Box 016)
    - 1. RG ts. 'dummy' layout of "20 Poems", pub. as Tottel's, No. 5 (September 1971), ed. Ron Silliman (some collected in RG's SENTENCES, Whale Cloth Press, 1978)
    - 2. RG ts. of page of poems (& xerox of same) from early SENTENCES period making big spatial cluster (rather than serial book format/organization) (see RG poster CAMBRIDGE M'ASS, Tuumba Press, 1979 for later result), (unpublished)
    - 3. Xerox of RG ts. selection of poems from ms. of Series (This Press, 1978), (unpublished as such)
  - E. RG selection of 17 poems as pub. in Alcheringa, New Series, Vol. 1, No. 2 (1975), ed. Dennis Tedlock & Jerome Rothenberg, in "The Dwelling Place: 9 Poets", ed. Ron Silliman (most collected in SENTENCES), (5 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - F. Three further RG investigations of visual/spatial presentation of poetic texts, (6 pp. total) (Box 016)
    - 1. Four RG ts. xerox enlargements of poems from SENTENCES ("s o m e o l d g u y s w i t h s c y t h e s", "walking down Washington Avenue", "actualities materialize", "kept on going to the corner store") [ca. 1975], (unpublished as such)
    - 2. Two RG xerox enlargements of William Carlos Williams' poems w/ visual emphases, "The Attic Which Is Desire" & "The Red Wheelbarrow" n.d., (used in teaching)
    - 3. RG spatial layout/paste-up of page of 7 poems from SENTENCES [ca. 1976], (w/ xerox page result) possibly for magazine presentation (which?) from (unpublished as such?)
  - G. RG holograph, ts. & xerox of ts. material regarding end of relation w/ Laura Wessner, from Summer 1976 (Oakland, CA) through Fall 1976 (Cambridge, MA), (26 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 016)
  - H. RG ts. selection, "136 separate poems from SENTENCES", pub. in boundary 2 (Robert Creeley issue), Vol. 6, No. 3/Vol. 7, No. 1 (Spring/Fall 1978), (selection made February 1977) (15 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - I. RG ts. poem "TWENTY YEARS/for S.L.Q." re reunion w/ 'high school sweetheart' Sallie Quan after (almost) 20 years 1977 Nov, (1 p. total) (unpublished) (Box 016)
  - J. Folder of RG ts. poems deleted from ms. of Series (This Press, 1978) [ca. 1977], (14 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 016)
  - K. RG tss. of some 'longer poems' from 1977 - 1978, (11 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 016)
    - 1. "Dog"
    - 2. Text beginning "Thought of turning off the bathwater..."
    - 3. "Description"
    - 4. "Twilight Progression Toward Reality"
    - 5. "New Haven"
    - 6. "P-Town Beach A Day Face South"
    - 7. "For Charles Olson / Late"
    - 8. "Back From Gloucester"
    - 9. "Poplars"
  - L. RG tss. of three poem sequences from 1978 re RG's 'hopeless romances' from that period, (10 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 016)
    - 1. "SEQUENCE: GIRL ARTIST / for M.A."
    - 2. "WAKING QUARTER TO FIVE / for A.H."
    - 3. "CAMBRIDGE M'ASS"
  - M. Large folder of RG ts. material from notebooks, some pub. in SENTENCES (Whale Cloth Press, 1978), many pub. in CAMBRIDGE M'ASS (Tuumba Press, 1979) 1977 - 1979, (144 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - N. RG ts./draft materials for CAMBRIDGE M'ASS, a selection from poems in VII.M. above, forming basis for RG's layout/making of offset master for 40" x 48" poster which is this work (Box 016)
  - O. RG ts. of selection of poems from Series, SENTENCES & CAMBRIDGE M'ASS, Probably for successful National Endowment for the Arts application (15 pp. total) (unpublished as such) (Box 016)
  - P. RG holograph/collage work "IF YOU / for Bob & Pen" from 1980 [ca. 1980], (1 p. total) (unpublished) (Box 016)
  - Q. Someone's (whose?) enlarged/altered photographs of eight poems from RG's SENTENCES, bringing out tactile qualities of typewriter images n.d., (8 pp. total) (unpublished?) (Box 016)
  - R. Two RG ts. poem sequences [ca. 1980's], (6 pp. total) (Box 016)
    - 1. "MORANDI / for Barrett Watten", (unpublished)(w/ xerox)
    - 2. "NARRATION", (unpublished) (w/ xerox of same)
  - S. RG selection/arrangement of material for Grenier/Eigner issue of Bezoar, Vol. 20, No. 4/Vol. 21, No. 1 1981 Feb, (38 pp. total) (Box 016)
    - 1. RG ts. of Larry Eigner poems for Bezoar
    - 2. RG ts. of xerox master of RG/LE material for Bezoar
    - 3. Issue of Bezoar made from RG xerox master
  - T. RG translation of excerpt from Bertolt Brecht's Das Badener Lehrstück Vom Einverständnis (The Baden-Baden Instructional Play Concerning Understanding), pub. in this, No. 11 (Spring 1981), performed by Poets Theater in San Francisco 1981 July 25 - 1981 July 26, (25 pp. total) (Box 016)
    - 1. RG ts. first draft, w/ RG holograph revisions
    - 2. RG ts. final draft
    - 3. Poster announcing Poets Theater performances
  - U. RG ts. selection from then ongoing project, A Day At The Beach, called "Further Beach Poem Drafts" pub. in Acts, No. 1 (June 1982) pub., ed. David Levi Strauss 1982 Feb 1, (10 pp. total) (xerox) (Box 016)
  - V. RG ts. of "BURNS' NIGHT HEARD / for Alastair & Nancy", pub. as Tansy 15 by John Moritz (April 1982), pub. also in Acts, No. 1 (June 1982), ed. David Levi Strauss, (3 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - W. RG unpublished poems from folder bearing RG annotation "some quite good" 1983 Spring - 1984, (holograph & ts.) (88 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - X. RG 'found poem' "SIXTEEN RUBBER TWO'S / from Kathleen Frumkin", built from KF note to RG, pub. in In Print, Vol. 4, No. 1 (Fall 1986), collected in RG's Phantom Anthems (0 Books, 1986), (6 pp. total) (Box 016)
    - 1. KF holograph note to RG n.d.
    - 2. RG holograph draft of poem n.d.
  - Y. RG holograph draft of poem "COMPUTER" (on brown shopping bag paper strips) from ca. 1987, pub. in What I Believe, RG issue of A*BACUS, No. 37 (October 1988), collected in RG's What I Relieve Transpiration/Transpiring Minnesota (0 Books, 1991), (4 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - Z. Fifteen RG holograph & ts. poems from What I Believe period 1988, (15 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - AA. Three RG color holograph drawing poems from beginning of r h y m m s period 1989, (5 pp. total) (Box 016)
    - 1. "MOONLIGHT BEAMING", dated January 1, 1989, pub. in Avec, Vol. 2, No. 1 (1989), ed. Cydney Chadwick, (black/white version of color holograph original)
    - 2. "20TH CENTURY / for John Bátki", pub. in Avec, Vol. 2, No. 1 (1989), ed. Cydney Chadwick, also reproduced in miniature & discussed briefly by Michael Davidson in his Ghostlier Demarcations (U. California Press, 1997)
    - 3. "WHAT EXISTS IN THE WORLD / for Emily & me", (unpublished)
  - AB. RG black/white xerox images from RG notebook (beginning of r h y m m s project), contains poems in Minnesota (0 Books, 1991)1989 Sept - 1989 Oct, (otherwise unpublished) (40 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - AC. RG black/white xerox images from RG notebook, of RG holograph drawing poems from r h y m m s project 1989 Nov - 1990 Jan, (many of which are now in red, black, blue & green in notebook) (unpublished) (41 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - AD. Two RG color holograph drawing poems from 1990 Feb, (beginning of r h y m m s period) (7 pp. total) (Box 016)
    - 1. "Moo", (w/ black & white xerox copy), pub. (in black/white version) in Gas (Winter 1990), ed. Kevin Opstedal & Charlie Ross
    - 2. "PUORPOSE / for Joanne Kyger", (w/ 2 black/white xerox copies) (unpublished)
  - AE. RG sequence of 4 poems for Fanny Howe, "SUN DOWN", "IMAGE", "BLUE EYES" & "was a rose" 1990 Spring, Pub. in Deluge, ed. Daniel McNaughton (4 pp. total) (black/white xerox images made from color holograph drawing poems) (Box 016)
  - AF. Seventeen RG color xerox image poems from beginning of r h y m m s project, annotated by RG "transitional work.. .not great" 1990 Fall, (13 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 016)
  - AG. RG color xerox images from notebook Drawing poems commenting/speculating on phrase of Robert Creeley's from end of RC introduction to Selected Poems "...the rest is silence" (U. California Press, 1991) 1991, (7 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 016)
  - AH. RG selection of poems made for Leslie Scalapino's 0, No. 4, Subliminal Time issue 1993, (black/white & color xerox images from notebook drawing poems) (20 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - AI. Folder containing RG writings ca. 1994, (7 pp. total) (Box 016)
    - 1. RG holograph dream notation beginning "DONALD G. etc...", (unpublished)
    - 2. RG black/white xerox images of two color drawing poems, ("Snake/bird" & "Fish/Hawk/With/Fish") pub. on line at Karl Young's Light & Dust website (in color)
    - 3. RG holograph poem "Travel/Where/You/Look", (unpublished)
    - 4. RG poem/note "ANTidote to I HATE SPEECH", (unpublished)
    - 5. RG color holograph poem "five/two/Nine"
  - AJ. RG color holograph Drawing poem "FOR EMILY LORD & ROBERT T.S. LOWELL" 1995 Fall, (w/ black & white xerox copy), pub. (in black/white version) in disturbed guillotine, No. 2 (Winter/Spring 1995-96), ed. Frederic Hausmann (2 pp. total) (Box 016)
  - AK. RG sequence "SAW-WHET OWLS", black/white xerox images from 4-color notebook drawing poems 1995, (4 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 016)
  - AL. RG holograph 'story', "A CONNECTION WITH SUSAN", February 1998, (xerox) (15 pp. total) (unpublished) (Box 016)
- Series VIII. RG Book Manuscripts 1967 - 1997, Drafts and finished versions of various texts, dated/chronologized and counted (by pages of text) in folders and binders - 2 boxes.
  - A. RG original ts. of RG's first book of poems, Dusk Road Games (Pym-Randall Press, 1967), w/ mock-up photo of cover (56 pp. total) (Box 018)
    (photo found by Emily Lord on trash night in Newtonville, MA)
  - B. Illustrated book made by Emily Lord in 1968 (?), (17 pp. total) (Box 018)
    Working from RG ms. then called "Coming and Going" (see VIII.C. below), partially realized, w/ photo of Emily, Bob & daughter Amy at Big Sur, July 4, 1968
  - C. RG ts. of ms. called Coming and Going, (76 pp. total) (Box 018)
    Mostly unpublished/ transitional poems between Dusk Road Games & Series (some in Series), written 1967-68 in England, Iowa & northern California
  - D. RG ts. of ms. called WATER FARMER, (96 pp. total) (Box 018)
    Being an expanded version of Coming and Going (see VIII.C. above)
  - E. RG ts. of ms. called WAVES, (101 pp. total) (Box 018)
    Many pub. in Series (This Press, 1978), written 1969-70 in northern California & travelling cross-country to & from New England
  - F. RG ts. of ms. called A DAY AT THE BEACH, (ca. 320 pp. total) (Box 018)
    ('UR' version/first draft), poems by RG/watercolors by Amy Grenier, written October 1969 - May 1970 during a number of day trips from Berkeley to Pacific beaches near Pigeon Point in San Mateo County (beginnings of project culminating in RG's completely different book, A Day At The Beach, Roof Books, 1985) (unpublished)
  - G. RG ts. of ms. called A DAY AT THE BEACH, (462 pp. total) (Box 018)
    ('UR' version/final draft), poems by RG (only), in two vols., being an expanded version of material in VIII.F. above, written October 1969 -January 1971, San Mateo beaches/Berkeley/New Hampshire/ Gloucester (unpublished)
  - H. RG ts. of ms. called FALL/WINTER FAMILY HOME, August 1970 - January 1971, (150 pp. total)
    RG poems written in Lanesville, MA, collected in Series (This Press, 1978)
  - I. Materials used by RG for production of magazine this, No. 2 (Fall 1971, (8 pp. total) (Box 018)
    In Franconia College printshop (see magazine in X.BF.2. below)
    - 1. Basis for page design (RG pencil marks)
    - 2. Amy Grenier drawing, used for front/back covers
    - 3. Postcard, used for title page
    - 4. Two pages from Finnish coloring book occurring as facing pages in this, No. 2
    - 5. Three Amy Grenier drawings
      Produced as half-tones at Littleton Courier shop in Littleton, NH & occurring in sequence in this, No. 2
  - J. RG original ts./'dummy' for RG production of magazine this, No. 3 (Fall 1972), (100 pp. total) (Box 018)
    In Franconia College printshop, typed on IBM Executive typewriter in President Leon Botstein's office (see magazine in X.BF.3. below)
  - K. RG original ts. of RG's book of poems, Series (This Press, 1978), (138 pp. total) (Box 018)
    Being RG selection from work written 1967 - 1971, w/ 3 cover designs for book by RG, John Bátki & Francie Shaw (Francie's was used) & 4 photomat shots of RG from early 1970's (n.b. a 'thing'/make facsimile edition)
  - L. Envelope containing materials re Barrett Watten's production of Series, including two letters from RG to BW (December 14 & 16, 1977), (29 pp. total) (Box 019)
    Discussing page design & enclosing a number of possible cover designs by RG & John Bátki (none used)
  - M. Envelope containing page proofs for Series, w/ letter from Barrett Watten to RG re book production 1978 June 13, (147 pp. total) (Box 019)
  - N. RG ts. of ms. called DOGTOWN, (146 pp. total) (Box 019)
    Mostly unpublished/transitional poems (a few in RG's SENTENCES), written March/April 1971 in Lanesville, MA
  - O. RG ts. of ms. called STICKY FINGERS / MAY NIGHTS / & / HOT SPRING, written in Spring 1971 in Lanesville, MA, (215 pp. total) (Box 019)
    Containing some pub. work ("Sticky Fingers" occurs in Series, a few poems in SENTENCES), very 'upbeat' overall
  - P. Materials relating to RG's edition of Robert Creeley's Selected Poems (Scribner's, 1976) & correspondence re ruination of book by Scribner's people, (200 pp. total) (Box 019)
    - 1. Xerox of RG ms, of Selected Poems (including RG ts. of suppressed introduction & original table of contents), showing RG selection from RC texts & correct sequence
    - 2. RC ts. letter to RG, September 1, 1975, proposing RG edit/make book
    - 3. RG holograph letter to RC, September 8, 1975 (xerox), enclosing first draft of Selected Poems
    - 4. RC holograph letter to RG, September 11, 1975, enclosing more poems for book
    - 5. Burroughs Mitchell (of Scribner's) ts. letter to RG, October 16, 1975, acknowledging RG participation/role
    - 6. RG ts. letter to Burroughs Mitchell, October 28, 1975, (xerox)
    - 7. BM ts. letter to RG, November 5, 1975
    - 8. BM ts. letter to RG, November 19, 1975, enclosing $500 payment for RG editorial work
    - 9. BM ts. letter to RG, December 3, 1975, acknowledging receipt of RG ms. of Selected Poems
    - 10. BM ts. letter to RG, September 20, 1976, re progress on book, promising to send proofs, etc.
    - 11. RG ts. letter to BM, October 19, 1976 (xerox), enclosing
    - 12. RG ts. letter to Patricia Cristol (of Scribner's) re book just out/'doctoring' of text by PC & others at Scribner's w/out notice to RC or RG
      (i.e., selection attributed to RC, all evidence of RG editing/making of book omitted, RG introduction dropped, crucial sequence of poems altered by art dept. etc.) (xerox of October 19, 1976 letter)
    - 13. RC holograph letter to RG, October 29, 1976, enclosing
    - 14. RC ts. letter to Charles Scribner, Jr., October 29, 1976, re whole debacle, (xerox)
    - 15. Patricia Cristol ts. letter to RG, October 29, 1976, apologizing for "our mistake" & pretending ignorance re alteration of RG original ms.
    - 16. BM ts. letter to RG, November 1, 1976, promising to credit RG as editor in future editions & asserting that "no change was made by the editorial department in the order of the poems that you laid out" (!)
    - 17. RG ts. letter to BM, November 4, 1976 enclosing xerox of contents pages of original RG ms., remarking variously on situation of Selected Poems, (xerox)
    - 18. BM ts. letter to RG, December 1, 1976, acknowledging changes in order of text "made in the Art Department"
    - 19. Lewis MacAdams holograph postcard to RG re book, from February 1976
  - Q. RG poem/prose sequence "NORTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE / for M.M." (Marion McCollom), written Winter 1975-76, (19 pp. total) (Box 019)
    Unique in RG's work for its narrative structure, pub. in this, No. 7 (Spring 1976), ed. Barrett Watten
    - 1. RG ts. of "NORTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE"
    - 2. Xerox of 'story' as it occurs in this, No. 7
  - R. Materials relating to RG page design ('copied' by Lyn Hejinian on her home letterpress) and making of RG book of poems, Oakland (Tuumba Press, 1980), (100 pp. total) (Box 019)
    - 1. 20 RG ts. poems on 5" x 8" index cards (recalling method of RG's SENTENCES) from Spring 1980, collecting toward book as a sort of first draft
    - 2. RG ts./paste-up page design for Oakland
    - 3. Xerox of RG page design for Oakland (a 'homemade book')
  - S. Materials relating to RG writing/production of essay on narrative/attention, ATTENTION / Seven Narratives, (156 pp. total) (Box 019)
    Pub. as Fascicle 28 in A Curriculum Of The Soul series (The Institute Of Further Studies, 1985)
    - 1. RG essay SEVEN NARRATIVES, written for Poetics Journal in response to request from co-editor Lyn Hejinian
      --RG holograph first draft (ca. September 1984). --RG ts. second draft w/ holograph revisions (Sept. '84). --RG ts. third draft w/ holograph revisions (Sept. '84). --RG ts. fourth draft w/ holograph revisions (Sept. '84). --Xerox of RG fifth draft w/ Barrett Watten (co-editor of Poetics Journal) holograph suggested revisions & RG holograph note concerning same/withdrawal of ms.
    - 2. RG essay ATTENTION / Seven Narratives, an expanded version of piece intended for Poetics Journal
      --Jack Clarke ts. letter to RG, March 24, 1984, proposing RG write Attention fascicle for A Curriculum Of The Soul. --JC ts. letter to RG, April 5, 1984, confirming same. --Xerox of RG holograph letter to JC, October 22, 1984, commenting on & enclosing. --RG ts. of "ATTENTION or NARRATION / NARRATION AS ATTENTION / SEVEN NARRATIVES" (w/ xerox of same). --JC ts. letter to RG, January 27, 1985 re ms. --JC holograph postcard to RG, February 13, 1985, conveying Albert Glover ok to publish essay. --Albert Glover ts. letter to RG, June 31, 1985. --AG ts. letter to RG, August 1985, enclosing 10 copies of Attention / Seven Narratives. --AG ts. letter to RG, August 30, 1985 re Curriculum Of The Soul project. --Signed copy of Attention / Seven Narratives fascicle.
  - T. Production materials relating to making of green box for RG r h y m m s project (Box 019)
    (designed to contain ca. 90 color xerox images of RG holograph drawing poems from 1989 on)
    - 1. Invoice from Custom Paper Products in San Leandro, CA dated August 23, 1991 for 520 r h y m m s boxes
    - 2. RG ts. 'master' for box spine, (w/ darker xerox images of same)
    - 3. RG holograph image " r h y m m s"
      Master' for box lid (w/ xerox images of same), used for box production.
  - U. Materials relating to RG's edition of Larry Eigner's windows / walls / yard / ways (Black Sparrow Press, 1994), (241 pp. total) (Box 019)
    - 1. Xerox of RG holograph letter to Michele Filshie of Black Sparrow, December 21, 1993
      Enclosing corrected first proofs & letter to person setting text, Sasha X.
    - 2. Xerox of RG ts. letter to Sasha X. regarding first proofs, December 21, 1993
      Translating typewriter spacing to letterpress & system of Larry Eigner's poems
    - 3. Xerox of corrected first proofs (w/ RG markings)
    - 4. Xerox of corrected third proofs (w/ RG markings)
  - V. RG ms. stages of composite work SOME 0' THAT, (172 pp. total) (Box 019)
    (unpublished as of April 1999)(for Leslie Scalapino), written/gathered in 1993 as an investigation/demonstration of some meanings/uses of strange word 'that' (& as a commentary on Leslie Scalapino's writing as well)
    - 1. RG largely holograph first draft, w/ 'contributions' from various hands in Bolinas poetry reading group (Joanne Kyger, Stephen Ratcliffe & others)
    - 2. RG ts. second draft w/ holograph additions
    - 3. RG ts. third draft w/ extensive holograph additions
      (w/ Fanny Howe holograph comment on work to this point)
    - 4. RG ts. fourth draft, substantially complete as of September 9, 1993
      (publish this version, exactly as shown, as offset/xerox edition, if time comes...)
  - W. History of making of RG issue of :that:, No. 24 (August 1994), (86 pp. total) (Box 019)
    Ed. Stephen Ellis & Stephen Dignazio